<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<?xml-stylesheet href="writer-resume.xsl" type="text/xsl" ?>
<resume>
  <overview>
    <title>Technical Communicator</title>
    <subtitle>UX/Technical Writer | Technical Editor | Content Strategist | User-Advocate</subtitle>
    <statement>Master of the best practices in technical communication with experience in structured authoring and the latest documentation technologies, I advocate for smart content that is reusable, searchable, and most of all, user-focused.</statement>
    <goal>My career goal is to continue to benefit business goals by delivering fast, professional content and by advising on content goals, usablity practices, and by providing new creative soultions now made possible by web services and cloud computing.</goal>
  </overview>
  <education>
    <degree>
      <school>University of North Texas</school>
      <alt_school>UNT</alt_school>
      <level>Master's of Art</level>
      <subject>Technical Communication</subject>
      <alt_name>MA in Technical Communication</alt_name>
      <year>2017</year>
      <gpa>3.8+</gpa>
      <summary>Established with user-centered approaches in technical communication, the coursework is a practicum on technical writing using the latest enterprise technologies.</summary>
    </degree>
    <degree>
      <school>University of Texas at Arlington</school>
      <alt_school>UTA</alt_school>
      <level>Bachelor's of Art</level>
      <subject>English and a Minor in Writing</subject>
      <alt_name>BA in English</alt_name>
      <year></year>
      <gpa></gpa>
      <summary>The coursework is built on an intense study of rhetoric and professional writing and communication.</summary>
    </degree>
  </education>
  <career>
    <position>
      <title>Sr. Technical Writer</title>
      <company>Renesas Electronics</company>
      <division></division>
      <date>January 2020 to present</date>
      <summary>Learned new technologies and workflows, continued to meet deadlines, and built consensus among the team and collaborators.</summary>
      <accomplishment>Led in merging the Renesas documentation team with the IDT technical writers.</accomplishment>
      <items>
        <item id="1">Learned and utilized ExtendScript, An Adobe-based Javascript framework to automate FrameMaker tasks.</item>
        <item id="2">Took administrative control of Workfront, an Adobe platform for enterprise manangement.</item>
        <item id="3">Learned to use Workfront to track and measure the documentation workflow.</item>
        <item id="4">Used the Oracle system Agile to process the document lifecycle.</item>
      </items>
    </position>
    <position>
      <title>Assistant Manager, Technical Publications</title>
      <company>Renesas Electronics</company>
      <division>Corporate Marketing</division>
      <date>January 2019 to December 2019</date>
      <summary>Working with a global team, I analyzed workflows, tracked metrics, diagnosed content management, and led the synthesization of the publishing workflow.</summary>
      <accomplishment>Transitioned Intersil documentation team to merge with Renesas documentation practices.</accomplishment>
      <items>
        <item id="1">Met with Tokyo team in San Jose to integrage template branding and seek opportunities for synthesis in workflow and content management.</item>
        <item id="1">Created web portal for the documentation team to host procedures, guidelines, and templates.</item>
        <item id="2">Hosted training documentation tools and guidelines with subject matter experts.</item>
        <item id="3">Led team in adopting branding guidelines, style, and technical writing principles in delieverables.</item>
        <item id="4">Built strong relationships with new team members through merger.</item>
      </items>
    </position>
    <position>
      <title>Technical Editor</title>
      <company>Renesas Electronics</company>
      <division>Corporate Marketing</division>
      <date>July 2018 to December 2018</date>
      <summary>Collaborated with technical writers, the marketing team, and subject matter experts to edit and publish both documentation and web content for high-profile product launches.</summary>
      <accomplishment>Learned quickly how to best edit highly technical content and then trained others.</accomplishment>
      <items>
        <item id="1">Used management system tools to track, analyze, and improve the documentation workflow</item>
        <item id="2">Built a database to survey and analyze the Intersil corpus of technical documentation</item>
        <item id="3">Utilized text analysis applications to survey the writing of over 4,000 documents.</item>
        <item id="4">Scripted a parser to convert technical data into DITA topics.</item>
        <item id="4">Built rapport with the team and led te meet deadlines during a corporate merger.</item>
      </items>
    </position>
  </career>
  <skills>
    <summary>In pushing to create clear, simple digital content for customers and end-users, my skillset and tools reflect my experience, education, and curiosity in the latest technologies.</summary>
    <tech_writing>
      <skill>Enterprise Publishing</skill>
      <skill>Web Publishing</skill>
      <skill>UX Writing</skill>
      <skill>Technical Editing</skill>
      <skill>Template Design</skill>
      <skill>Copyediting</skill>
      <skill>Print Design</skill>
    </tech_writing>
    <leadership>
      <skill>Enterprise Workflow Management</skill>
      <skill>Content Strategy</skill>
      <skill>Data-based Analytics</skill>
      <skill>Usablity Testing</skill>
      <skill>Audience Analysis</skill>
      <skill>Heuristic Evaluations</skill>
      <skill>Style Management</skill>
    </leadership>
    <documents>
      <skill>Customer-focused Content</skill>
      <skill>Digital Content</skill>
      <skill>Marketing Deliverables</skill>
      <skill>Datasheets</skill>
      <skill>Software Manuals</skill>
      <skill>Hardware Manuals</skill>
      <skill>Specifications</skill>
      <skill>Procedures</skill>
    </documents>
    <tools>
      <skill>Document Management Systems</skill>
      <skill>Content Management Systems</skill>
      <skill>Adobe FrameMaker</skill>
      <skill>Acrobat Pro</skill>
      <skill>Dreamweaver</skill>
      <skill>Illustrator</skill>
      <skill>Photoshop</skill>
      <skill>Visio</skill>
      <skill>Code/Markdown Editors</skill>
      <skill>Microsoft Word and Excel</skill>
    </tools>
    <software>
      <skill>MAC OS</skill>
      <skill>Windows OS</skill>
      <skill>Git</skill>
      <skill>Git BASH</skill>
      <skill>Powershell</skill>
      <skill>Atom</skill>
      <skill>Brackets</skill>
    </software>
    <code>
      <skill>XML / DITA</skill>
      <skill>Markdown</skill>
      <skill>HTML and CSS</skill>
      <skill>XLST / XQuery</skill>
      <skill>XML/XHTML Parsers</skill>
      <skill>Some Ruby on Rails</skill>
      <skill>Some JavaScript</skill>
      <skill>Some PHP</skill>
    </code>
    <softskills>
      <skill>Level-headed team player under pressure</skill>
      <skill>Relentless advocate for customers and users</skill>
      <skill>Collaborator with team and global divisions</skill>
      <skill>Reaches across teams to solve problems</skill>
      <skill>Works to develop creative technical solutions</skill>
      <skill>Promoter of single-source technologies</skill>
    </softskills>
    <ux>
      <skill>UX Writing</skill>
      <skill>Usability Testing</skill>
      <skill>Audience Analysis</skill>
      <skill>Wireframing</skill>
      <skill>Heuristic Evaluations</skill>
    </ux>
  </skills>
</resume>
