<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<?xml-stylesheet href="writer-resume.xsl" type="text/xsl" ?>
<resume>
  <overview>
    <title>Technical Communicator</title>
    <subtitle>UX/Technical Writer | Technical Editor | Content Strategist | User-Advocate</subtitle>
    <statement>A master of the best practices in technical communication with advanced experience in structured authoring and single-source technologies, I advocate for smart content that is reusable, searchable, and most of all, user-focused.</statement>
    <goal>My aim is to continue to benefit business goals by delivering fast, professional content, and by advising on content goals, usability practices,  and technical communication solutions now made possible by web services and cloud computing.</goal>
  </overview>
  <education>
    <degree>
      <school>University of North Texas</school>
      <alt_school>UNT</alt_school>
      <level>Master's of Art</level>
      <subject>Technical Communication</subject>
      <alt_name>MA in Technical Communication</alt_name>
      <year>2017</year>
      <gpa>3.8+</gpa>
      <summary>Established with user-centered approaches in technical communication, the coursework is a practicum on technical writing using the latest enterprise technologies.</summary>
    </degree>
    <degree>
      <school>University of Texas at Arlington</school>
      <alt_school>UTA</alt_school>
      <level>Bachelor's of Art</level>
      <subject>English with a Minor in Writing</subject>
      <alt_name>BA in English</alt_name>
      <year></year>
      <gpa></gpa>
      <summary>The coursework is built on an intense study of rhetoric, persuasive writing, and professional communication.</summary>
    </degree>
  </education>
  <career>
    <position>
      <title>Sr. Technical Writer</title>
      <company>Renesas Electronics</company>
      <division>Corporate Marketing</division>
      <date>January 2020 to present</date>
      <summary>Learned new technologies and workflows, continued to meet deadlines, and built consensus among the team and collaborators.</summary>
      <accomplishment>Led in merging the Renesas documentation team with the IDT technical writers.</accomplishment>
      <items>
        <item>Learned and utilized ExtendScript, an Adobe-based JavaScript framework to automate FrameMaker tasks.</item>
        <item>Took administrative control of Workfront, an Adobe platform for enterprise manangement.</item>
        <item>Learned to use Workfront to track and measure the documentation workflow.</item>
        <item>Used the Oracle system Agile to process the document lifecycle.</item>
      </items>
    </position>
    <position>
      <title>Assistant Manager, Technical Publications</title>
      <company>Renesas Electronics</company>
      <division>Corporate Marketing</division>
      <date>January 2019 to December 2019</date>
      <summary>Working with a global team, I analyzed workflows, tracked metrics, diagnosed content management, and synthesized the publishing workflow.</summary>
      <accomplishment>Transitioned Intersil documentation team to merge with Renesas documentation practices.</accomplishment>
      <items>
        <item>Met with Tokyo team in San Jose to integrate template branding and seek opportunities for synthesis in workflow and content management.</item>
        <item>Created web portal for the documentation team to host procedures, guidelines, and templates.</item>
        <item>Hosted training documentation tools and guidelines with subject matter experts.</item>
        <item>Led team in adopting branding guidelines, style, and technical writing principles in deliverables.</item>
        <item>Built strong relationships with new team members through merger.</item>
      </items>
    </position>
    <position>
      <title>Technical Editor</title>
      <company>Renesas Electronics</company>
      <division>Corporate Marketing</division>
      <date>July 2018 to December 2018</date>
      <summary>Collaborated with technical writers, the marketing team, and subject matter experts to edit and publish both documentation and web content for high-profile product launches.</summary>
      <accomplishment>Learned quickly highly-technical content and worked to improve the writing style using technical writing principles.</accomplishment>
      <items>
        <item>Used management system tools to track, analyze, and improve the documentation workflow.</item>
        <item>Built a database to survey and analyze the Intersil corpus of technical documentation.</item>
        <item>Utilized text analysis applications to survey the writing of over 4,000 documents.</item>
        <item>Built rapport with the team and led to meet deadlines during a corporate merger.</item>
        <item>Scripted a parser to convert technical data into DITA topics.</item>
      </items>
    </position>
    <position>
      <title>UX Designer</title>
      <company>Rockfish Digital</company>
      <division>UX Team</division>
      <date>October to November 2017</date>
      <summary>For the digital marketing agency, I designed wireframes and customer journeys with both data-based research and collaboration with the content strategist, design lead, developer, and UX lead. My projects focused on creating user-centered solutions that met marketing and usability goals for high-profile national brands.</summary>
      <accomplishment>Contributed immediately to help a short-handed team meet deadlines for Banfield Pet Hospital and Hershey's.</accomplishment>
      <items>
        <item>Worked quickly to understand expectations and previous research that would inform my own deliverables.</item>
        <item>Using Sketch, built 10 dynamic wireframes to facilitate a library of veterinarian research publications and marketing content.</item>
        <item>Collaborated in workshops and meetings with the design team and client to create professional deliverables that met critical deadlines.</item>
        <item>Analyzed and synthesized months of research into 4 customer journeys for online grocery platforms.</item>
      </items>
    </position>
    <position>
      <title>UX Researcher</title>
      <company>Harman Intl. (now a Samsung company)</company>
      <division>UX Team</division>
      <date>June to September 2017</date>
      <summary>With the Harman UX team, I assisted with a 4-month user-centered research project that evaluated the use of software platforms in the design, implementation, and maintenance of audio/video (AV) control networks.</summary>
      <accomplishment>Synthesized months of UX research into professional deliverables that informed a 2-day design mapping workshop with key clients and stakeholders.</accomplishment>
      <items>
        <item>Collaborated with stakeholders in both the Los Angeles and New York offices.</item>
        <item>Evaluated competitor software and conducted heuristic evaluations of Harman's AV and control software.</item>
        <item>Managed participants, conducted stakeholder interviews, organized surveys, and assisted with contextual inquiries across 4 metropolitan areas.</item>
        <item>Conducted moderated and remote usability testing and provided quantitative and qualitative-based insight with presentations and deliverables.</item>
      </items>
    </position>
    <position>
      <title>Designer/Content Consultant</title>
      <company>DART</company>
      <division>Corporate Marketing</division>
      <date>May 2017</date>
      <summary>For the DART Marketing team, I consulted on the rail system’s new transit application in order to improve the user flow, usability, and UI design of the popular mobile app.</summary>
      <accomplishment>With a two-day deadline, impacted the design by producing a deliverable based on research and usability principles.</accomplishment>
      <items>
        <item>Utilizing the Invision prototype, I evaluated the current state of the application by applying a set criteria of mobile heuristics.</item>
        <item>Conducted a competitive analysis of similar applications to inform common application tasks such as user registration, onboarding, and purchases.</item>
        <item>Synthesized findings with categories of user flow, usability, and UI design into deliverables for the marketing and development teams.</item>
        <item>Collaborated closely with the marketing lead to best understand her needs and expectations.</item>
      </items>
    </position>
    <position>
      <title>UI / Web Editor (Internship)</title>
      <company>Memorial Hermann</company>
      <division>Corporate Marketing</division>
      <date>December 2016 to March 2017</date>
      <summary>For the largest non-profit healthcare system in Texas, I maintained and implemented the online style guide, coded responsive web pages with HTML, CSS, and the CMS content editor, created web banners for the site and social media, implemented usability recommendations, collaborated with 12 departments to update existing content, and wireframed content for new departmental sites.</summary>
      <accomplishment>Working on a variety of projects, I worked closely across departments to develop user-focused web content.</accomplishment>
      <items>
        <item>Using SEO practices, collaborated with marketing leads with tools such as Moz, Wistia, and WordStream to produce content that drives consumer traffic.</item>
        <item>Created personas and wireframes to inform the development of a new online presence, the Special Pharmacy.</item>
        <item>Analyzed and implemented usability recommendations for the Ironman Sports Medicine Institute.</item>
        <item>Edited and maintained web content for 12 administrative departments.</item>
      </items>
    </position>
    <position>
      <title>Web Developer</title>
      <company>UNT</company>
      <division>DSA Marketing</division>
      <date>June 2015 to August 2016</date>
      <summary>I collaborated with 25 departmental heads to create and maintain content for their sites, analyzed analytical data for the site's 43,000 monthly visitors to produce design recommendations, and used Illustrator, Photoshop, Dreamweaver, Bootstrap, and the Drupal CMS to design and develop content.</summary>
      <accomplishment>With the position unexpectedly vacant, I filled it and learned quickly to use PHP, Bootstrap, and Dreamweaver to maintain the existing workflow for the university administration.</accomplishment>
      <items>
        <item>Conducted user research including multiple card sorts to create recommendations for the site redesign.</item>
        <item>Utilized Google Analytics data to inform design and content decisions.</item>
        <item>Maintained the use of Bootstrap to develop a mobile-first design.</item>
        <item>Worked closely with department leads to understand their priorities and content needs.</item>
      </items>
    </position>
  </career>
  <skills>
    <summary>In pushing to create clear, simple digital content for customers and end-users, my skill set and tools reflect my experience, education, and curiosity in the latest technologies.</summary>
    <tech_writing>
      <skill>Enterprise Publishing</skill>
      <skill>Web Publishing</skill>
      <skill>UX Writing</skill>
      <skill>Technical Editing</skill>
      <skill>Template Design</skill>
      <skill>Copyediting</skill>
      <skill>Print Design</skill>
    </tech_writing>
    <leadership>
      <skill>Enterprise Workflow Management</skill>
      <skill>Content Strategy</skill>
      <skill>Data-based Analytics</skill>
      <skill>Usability Testing</skill>
      <skill>Audience Analysis</skill>
      <skill>Heuristic Evaluations</skill>
      <skill>Style Management</skill>
    </leadership>
    <documents>
      <skill>Customer-focused Content</skill>
      <skill>Digital Content</skill>
      <skill>Marketing Deliverables</skill>
      <skill>Datasheets</skill>
      <skill>Software Manuals</skill>
      <skill>Hardware Manuals</skill>
      <skill>Specifications</skill>
      <skill>Procedures</skill>
    </documents>
    <tools>
      <skill>Document Management Systems</skill>
      <skill>Content Management Systems</skill>
      <skill>Adobe FrameMaker</skill>
      <skill>Acrobat Pro</skill>
      <skill>Dreamweaver</skill>
      <skill>Illustrator</skill>
      <skill>Photoshop</skill>
      <skill>Visio</skill>
      <skill>Code/Markdown Editors</skill>
      <skill>Microsoft Word and Excel</skill>
    </tools>
    <software>
      <skill>MAC OS</skill>
      <skill>Windows OS</skill>
      <skill>Git</skill>
      <skill>Git BASH</skill>
      <skill>Powershell</skill>
      <skill>Atom</skill>
      <skill>Brackets</skill>
    </software>
    <code>
      <skill>XML / DITA</skill>
      <skill>Markdown</skill>
      <skill>HTML and CSS</skill>
      <skill>XLST / XQuery</skill>
      <skill>XML/XHTML Parsers</skill>
      <skill>Some Ruby on Rails</skill>
      <skill>Some JavaScript</skill>
      <skill>Some PHP</skill>
    </code>
    <softskills>
      <skill>Level-headed team player under pressure</skill>
      <skill>Relentless advocate for customers and users</skill>
      <skill>Collaborator with team and global divisions</skill>
      <skill>Reaches across teams to solve problems</skill>
      <skill>Works to develop creative technical solutions</skill>
      <skill>Promoter of single-source technologies</skill>
    </softskills>
    <ux>
      <skill>UX Writing</skill>
      <skill>UX Research</skill>
      <skill>Usability Testing</skill>
      <skill>Audience Analysis</skill>
      <skill>Wireframing</skill>
      <skill>Heuristic Evaluations</skill>
    </ux>
  </skills>
</resume>
